<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>german anki flashcards on Monoglot Anxiety</title>
    <link>https://www.monoglotanxiety.com/tags/german-anki-flashcards/</link>
    <description>Recent content in german anki flashcards on Monoglot Anxiety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 19:17:30 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.monoglotanxiety.com/tags/german-anki-flashcards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Booster pack: German hiking vocabulary</title>
      <link>https://www.monoglotanxiety.com/blog/booster-pack-german-hiking-vocabulary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 19:17:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.monoglotanxiety.com/blog/booster-pack-german-hiking-vocabulary/</guid>
      <description>Hiking has been an escape for me throughout the pandemic, and I like to imagine where I might go hiking once this is over. I suppose we&amp;rsquo;re at the &amp;ldquo;sanguine tourism fantasies&amp;rdquo; stage of covid-19… Anyways, all that daydreaming inspired this booster pack of German hiking vocabulary. Even though travel restrictions mean most of us won&amp;rsquo;t be flying off to hike in the Alps anytime soon, we can at least upgrade our pandemic daydreams with a dose of linguistic authenticity!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conditional formatting based on field content for Anki flashcards</title>
      <link>https://www.monoglotanxiety.com/blog/conditional-formatting-based-on-field-content-for-anki-flashcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 10:06:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.monoglotanxiety.com/blog/conditional-formatting-based-on-field-content-for-anki-flashcards/</guid>
      <description>Anki allows conditoinal formatting based on whether or not fields are empty, but you’ll need to use a bit of code to change your cards based on field content. Luckily, it’s not that hard, and using this trick you can conditionally display text as well. I use it to color-code my German flashcards by noun gender without having to do everything by hand.
Out-of-the-box, Anki supports &amp;ldquo;conditional replacement,&amp;rdquo; which changes what gets rendered on a card is based on whether or not fields are empty.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
