<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>german anki flashcards on Monoglot Anxiety</title>
    <link>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/tags/german-anki-flashcards/</link>
    <description>Recent content in german anki flashcards on Monoglot Anxiety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 19:17:30 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/tags/german-anki-flashcards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Booster pack: German hiking vocabulary</title>
      <link>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/booster-pack-german-hiking-vocabulary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 19:17:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/booster-pack-german-hiking-vocabulary/</guid>
      <description>Given covid-19 related travel restrictions, not too many people who don&amp;rsquo;t already live near the Alps are going to be visiting anytime soon. But at least this month&amp;rsquo;s booster pack will upgrade your pandemic daydreams with a dose of linguistic authenticity!
Hiking is a popular tourist activity in Germany, and there are a few well-known routes like the Mittelweg that are definitely on my bucket list. But interestingly, despite its famous hilltop Disney castles and alpine waterfalls so instagrammable they are literally to die for, Germany is mostly not a mountain country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conditional formatting based on field content for Anki flashcards</title>
      <link>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/conditional-formatting-based-on-field-content-for-anki-flashcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 10:06:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/conditional-formatting-based-on-field-content-for-anki-flashcards/</guid>
      <description>Anki allows conditoinal formatting based on whether or not fields are empty, but you’ll need to use a bit of code to change your cards based on field content. Luckily, it’s not that hard, and using this trick you can conditionally display text as well. I use it to color-code my German flashcards by noun gender without having to do everything by hand.
Out-of-the-box, Anki supports &amp;ldquo;conditional replacement,&amp;rdquo; which changes what gets rendered on a card is based on whether or not fields are empty.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
