<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>how to practice a language on Monoglot Anxiety</title>
    <link>https://www.monoglotanxiety.com/tags/how-to-practice-a-language/</link>
    <description>Recent content in how to practice a language on Monoglot Anxiety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 17:49:13 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.monoglotanxiety.com/tags/how-to-practice-a-language/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>11 ways to practice writing in a foreign language</title>
      <link>https://www.monoglotanxiety.com/blog/11-ways-to-practice-writing-in-a-foreign-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 17:49:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.monoglotanxiety.com/blog/11-ways-to-practice-writing-in-a-foreign-language/</guid>
      <description>Learning to write in a new laguage can be intimidating, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re learning alone. Like speaking, writing is a productive skill which makes it impossible to learn passively. Reading will improve your writing, to be sure. But if you want to write, you need to write!
But what to write?
Figuring that out is the tough bit. And given that writers block can easily strike even when writing in our native languages, sitting down in front of a blank page to scribble something down in a new language can feel downright impossible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Duolingo bad?</title>
      <link>https://www.monoglotanxiety.com/blog/is-duolingo-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 18:18:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.monoglotanxiety.com/blog/is-duolingo-bad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is Duolingo bad? You&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard a lot of criticisms of this popular app if you&amp;rsquo;ve been hanging around language learning communities online. Duolingo gets a lot of flack, and there&amp;rsquo;s good reason for that. Nobody is going to reach fluency in a foreign language just by using a game app, and a lot of Duolingo users seem to think they can. Still, I think many critics miss an important point: Duolingo scratches the phone itch. And that&amp;rsquo;s no small thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
