<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>German Booster Packs on Monoglot Anxiety</title>
    <link>https://www.monoglotanxiety.com/ankidecks/german-booster-packs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in German Booster Packs on Monoglot Anxiety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 11:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.monoglotanxiety.com/ankidecks/german-booster-packs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Booster Pack: German tree vocabulary</title>
      <link>https://www.monoglotanxiety.com/blog/booster-pack-german-tree-vocabulary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 11:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.monoglotanxiety.com/blog/booster-pack-german-tree-vocabulary/</guid>
      <description>When we learn a new language, we focus on learning the words we actually need to communicate. But eventually, you might want to be able to get across points like &amp;ldquo;pine tree&amp;rdquo; without having to say things like &amp;ldquo;der Baum, der Nadeln statt Blätter hat.&amp;rdquo;
This week&amp;rsquo;s booster pack is a deck full of eventually words involving trees—both the German names for specific types of trees and the German words for parts of trees like roots and branches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Booster pack: German hiking vocabulary</title>
      <link>https://www.monoglotanxiety.com/blog/booster-pack-german-hiking-vocabulary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 19:17:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.monoglotanxiety.com/blog/booster-pack-german-hiking-vocabulary/</guid>
      <description>Hiking has been an escape for me throughout the pandemic, and I like to imagine where I might go hiking once this is over. I suppose we&amp;rsquo;re at the &amp;ldquo;sanguine tourism fantasies&amp;rdquo; stage of covid-19… Anyways, all that daydreaming inspired this free Anki deck of German hiking vocabulary. Even though travel restrictions mean most of us won&amp;rsquo;t be flying off to hike in the Alps anytime soon, we can at least upgrade our pandemic daydreams with a dose of linguistic authenticity!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Booster Pack: German words for drunk</title>
      <link>https://www.monoglotanxiety.com/blog/booster-pack-german-words-for-drunk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 20:30:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.monoglotanxiety.com/blog/booster-pack-german-words-for-drunk/</guid>
      <description>Depending on your stereotypes of German speakers, you may or may not be surprised to learn that there are a lot of German words for drunk. This post walks through 18 of them as well as words for discussing the aftermath of a night out. I&amp;rsquo;ve also put them together as a neat set of free Anki cards so you might have a shot at remembering them when the time comes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
