<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anki on Monoglot Anxiety</title>
    <link>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/categories/anki/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anki on Monoglot Anxiety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 15:20:02 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/categories/anki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Anki template for German that automatically generates cloze deletions and color-codes nouns</title>
      <link>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/anki-format-for-german-that-automatically-generates-cloze-deletions-and-color-codes-nouns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 15:20:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/anki-format-for-german-that-automatically-generates-cloze-deletions-and-color-codes-nouns/</guid>
      <description>One of my major frustrations with Anki is the stiffness of cloze-formatted cards. They just don&amp;rsquo;t play nice with basic card types. And while I often want to incorperate cloze deletions into my decks, making seperate notes for clozes of my example sentences is simply beyond my effort tolerance. So instead of spending an extra 30sec/card, I did the lazy thing and spent an extra week figuring out how to get basic cards to automatically make cloze deletions based on example sentences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conditional formatting based on field content for Anki flashcards</title>
      <link>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/conditional-formatting-based-on-field-content-for-anki-flashcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 10:06:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/conditional-formatting-based-on-field-content-for-anki-flashcards/</guid>
      <description>Anki allows conditoinal formatting based on whether or not fields are empty, but you’ll need to use a bit of code to change your cards based on field content. Luckily, it’s not that hard, and using this trick you can conditionally display text as well. I use it to color-code my German flashcards by noun gender without having to do everything by hand.
Out-of-the-box, Anki supports &amp;ldquo;conditional replacement,&amp;rdquo; which changes what gets rendered on a card is based on whether or not fields are empty.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
