<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monoglot Anxiety</title>
    <link>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Monoglot Anxiety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 10:06:21 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Conditional formatting based on field content for Anki flashcards</title>
      <link>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/conditional-formatting-based-on-field-content-for-anki-flashcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 10:06:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/conditional-formatting-based-on-field-content-for-anki-flashcards/</guid>
      <description>Anki allows conditoinal formatting based on whether or not fields are empty, but you’ll need to use a bit of code to change your cards based on field content. Luckily, it’s not that hard, and using this trick you can conditionally display text as well. I use it to color-code my German flashcards by noun gender without having to do everything by hand.
Out-of-the-box, Anki supports &amp;ldquo;conditional replacement,&amp;rdquo; which changes what gets rendered on a card is based on whether or not fields are empty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Duolingo bad? Maybe, but it&#39;s still worth downloading</title>
      <link>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/is-duolingo-bad-maybe-but-its-still-worth-downloading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 18:18:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/is-duolingo-bad-maybe-but-its-still-worth-downloading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Duolingo gets a lot of flack in some corners of the language-learning internet, and there&amp;rsquo;s good reason for that. Nobody is going to reach fluency in a foreign language just by using a game app. Still, I think many critics miss an important point: Duolingo scratches the phone itch. And that&amp;rsquo;s no small thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fehler Files: German Dative Plural</title>
      <link>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/fehler-files-1-german-dative-plural/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/fehler-files-1-german-dative-plural/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a bit of a language coward. I started learning German on my own, and for the longest time I didn&amp;rsquo;t speak at all despite developing rather good comprehension. It&amp;rsquo;s not like I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have tried, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t. I was just too scared of embarrassing myself. Eventually, I hired a tutor to get some speech practice, and only after that did I finally work up the courage to start practicing with my boyfriend.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/about/</guid>
      <description>Being the good cornfed American girl that I am, I didn&amp;rsquo;t learn a second language growing up, and I ended up develop a nasty case of I now affectionately call monoglot anxiety: a sort of wallowing, often jealous panic surrounding having never learned to speak a second language, and fear of inevitably screwing up all the time if I did try to learn one.
For years, it held me back, but eventually, it drove me bonkers enough to grind to the end of Duolingo German.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
