<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>German on Monoglot Anxiety</title>
    <link>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/categories/german/</link>
    <description>Recent content in German on Monoglot Anxiety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 15:20:02 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/categories/german/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Anki template for German that automatically generates cloze deletions and color-codes nouns</title>
      <link>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/anki-format-for-german-that-automatically-generates-cloze-deletions-and-color-codes-nouns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 15:20:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/anki-format-for-german-that-automatically-generates-cloze-deletions-and-color-codes-nouns/</guid>
      <description>One of my major frustrations with Anki is the stiffness of cloze-formatted cards. They just don&amp;rsquo;t play nice with basic card types. So while I often want to incorperate cloze deletions into my decks, making seperate notes for clozes of my example sentences is simply beyond my effort tolerance. So instead of spending an extra 30sec/card, I did the clearly easier thing and spent a week figuring out how to get basic cards to automatically make cloze deletions based on example sentences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fehler Files: Talking about talking</title>
      <link>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/fehler-files-talking-about-talking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 18:31:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/fehler-files-talking-about-talking/</guid>
      <description>Clawing my brain apart trying to remember whether a verb takes the dative or accusative case is one of those universal German-learning struggles that I imagine inspired the whole &amp;ldquo;Deutsche Sprache, schwere Sprache&amp;rdquo; idea. And I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that many of the words that most often initiate a holy-$h!#-what-case-do-I-use death-spiral are the common verbs describing speech: sagen, fragen, and co.
The funny thing is, these verbs actually mostly–and I&amp;rsquo;ll&amp;rsquo;get to the mostly bit–behave according to the usual rules dictating case in German.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Duolingo bad? Maybe, but it&#39;s still worth downloading</title>
      <link>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/is-duolingo-bad-maybe-but-its-still-worth-downloading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 18:18:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/is-duolingo-bad-maybe-but-its-still-worth-downloading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Duolingo gets a lot of flack in some corners of the language-learning internet, and there&amp;rsquo;s good reason for that. Nobody is going to reach fluency in a foreign language just by using a game app. Still, I think many critics miss an important point: Duolingo scratches the phone itch. And that&amp;rsquo;s no small thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fehler Files: German Dative Plural</title>
      <link>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/fehler-files-1-german-dative-plural/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/fehler-files-1-german-dative-plural/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a bit of a language coward. I started learning German on my own, and for the longest time I didn&amp;rsquo;t speak at all despite developing rather good comprehension. It&amp;rsquo;s not like I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have tried, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t. I was just too scared of embarrassing myself. Eventually, I hired a tutor to get some speech practice, and only after that did I finally work up the courage to start practicing with my boyfriend.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
