<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>language learning tips on Monoglot Anxiety</title>
    <link>https://monoglotanxiety.com/tags/language-learning-tips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in language learning tips on Monoglot Anxiety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Monoglot Anxiety | Copyright Elise Cutts 2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 15:40:24 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://monoglotanxiety.com/tags/language-learning-tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to  make better language flashcards by combining writing practice with spaced repetition</title>
      <link>https://monoglotanxiety.com/post/spaced-repetition-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 15:40:24 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monoglotanxiety.com/post/spaced-repetition-writing/</guid>
      <description>Writing is one of my favorite ways to actively study German. It is great for vocabulary building and grammar practice, and in the absence of speaking opportunities, it is the only way to get practice with production skills. But beyond simply being a great way to practice on its own, writing is a key component of how I use flashcards and spaced repetition to learn German.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11 ways to practice writing in your target language</title>
      <link>https://monoglotanxiety.com/post/11-ways-to-practice-writing-in-a-foreign-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 15:40:24 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monoglotanxiety.com/post/11-ways-to-practice-writing-in-a-foreign-language/</guid>
      <description>Learning to write in a new laguage can be intimidating, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re learning alone. Like speaking, writing is a productive skill which makes it impossible to learn passively. Reading will improve your writing, to be sure. But if you want to write, you need to write!
But what to write?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A candid review of Pimsleur Danish</title>
      <link>https://monoglotanxiety.com/post/pimsleur-danish-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 15:40:24 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monoglotanxiety.com/post/pimsleur-danish-review/</guid>
      <description>I received a lot of reccomendations of the Pimsleur language programs from family members back when I was preparing to head to Denmark in 2019. So naturally, I picked up Pimsleur Danish 1, never finished it, and forgot about it until about a month ago when I found the little blue Pimsleur logo lurking in my app drawer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Duolingo bad?</title>
      <link>https://monoglotanxiety.com/post/is-duolingo-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 15:40:24 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monoglotanxiety.com/post/is-duolingo-bad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is Duolingo bad? You&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard a lot of criticisms of this popular app if you&amp;rsquo;ve been hanging around language learning communities online. Duolingo gets a lot of flack, and there&amp;rsquo;s good reason for that. Nobody is going to reach fluency in a foreign language just by using a game app, and a lot of Duolingo users seem to think they can. Still, I think many critics miss an important point: Duolingo scratches the phone itch. And that&amp;rsquo;s no small thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
