<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grammar on Monoglot Anxiety</title>
    <link>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/categories/grammar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Grammar on Monoglot Anxiety</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 20:30:24 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/categories/grammar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Voabulary booster pack: German words that mean &#39;drunk&#39;</title>
      <link>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/booster-pack-german-words-for-drunk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 20:30:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/booster-pack-german-words-for-drunk/</guid>
      <description>Depending on your stereotypes of German speakers, you may or may not be surprised to learn that there are a lot of words that mean &amp;ldquo;drunk&amp;rdquo; in German. This post walks through 18 of them as well as words for discussing the aftermath of a night out. I&amp;rsquo;ve also put them together as a neat set of Anki cards so you might have a shot at remembering them when the time comes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fehler Files: Talking about talking in German</title>
      <link>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/fehler-files-talking-about-talking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 18:31:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/fehler-files-talking-about-talking/</guid>
      <description>Clawing my brain apart trying to remember whether a verb takes the dative or accusative case is one of those universal German-learning struggles that I imagine inspired the whole &amp;ldquo;Deutsche Sprache, schwere Sprache&amp;rdquo; idea. And I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that many of the words that most often initiate a holy-$h!#-what-case-do-I-use death-spiral are the common verbs describing speech: sagen, fragen, and co.
The funny thing is, these verbs actually mostly–and I&amp;rsquo;ll&amp;rsquo;get to the mostly bit–behave according to the usual rules dictating case in German.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fehler Files: the German Dative Plural</title>
      <link>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/fehler-files-1-german-dative-plural/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suspicious-galileo-91919d.netlify.app/blog/fehler-files-1-german-dative-plural/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a bit of a language coward. I started learning German on my own, and for the longest time I didn&amp;rsquo;t speak at all despite developing rather good comprehension. It&amp;rsquo;s not like I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have tried, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t. I was just too scared of embarrassing myself. Eventually, I hired a tutor to get some speech practice, and only after that did I finally work up the courage to start practicing with my boyfriend.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
